<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biochar case studies on Biochar Systems</title>
    <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biochar case studies on Biochar Systems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;#169; Elias S. Azzi, Cecilia Sundberg, KTH, SLU</copyright><atom:link href="https://biochar.systems/case-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stockholm - Prospective life cycle assessment of large-scale biochar production and use on dairy farms</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/1-stockholm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/1-stockholm/</guid>
      <description>Resources Reference Azzi ES, Karltun E, Sundberg C (2019) Prospective life cycle assessment of large-scale biochar production and use for negative emissions in Stockholm. Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology 53:8466–8476. DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lindeborgs - Biochar production potential, variability and environmental performance at the farm level </title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/2-lindeborgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/2-lindeborgs/</guid>
      <description>Resources Reference Azzi ES, Karltun E, Sundberg C (2021) Small-scale biochar production on Swedish farms: A model for estimating potential, variability, and environmental performance. Journal of Cleaner Production 280:124873. DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helsingborg - Biochar produced from wood waste for soil remediation</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/3-helsingborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/3-helsingborg/</guid>
      <description>Resources Reference Papageorgiou A, Azzi ES, Enell A, Sundberg C (2021) Biochar produced from wood waste for soil remediation in Sweden: carbon sequestration and other environmental impacts. Science of the Total Environment 145953.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uppsala - Urban uses of biochar</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/4-uppsala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/4-uppsala/</guid>
      <description>Resources Reference Azzi ES, Karltun E, Sundberg C (2022). Life cycle assessment of urban uses of biochar and case study in Uppsala, Sweden. Biochar, 4(1), 18. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1007/s42773-022-00144-3
Download citation as RIS  Download as pre-print PDF Presentations The work was presented at a conference and several workshops, for different target audiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and where to apply biochar in Sweden: exploring different narratives</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/5-gis-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/5-gis-sweden/</guid>
      <description>Resources Reference Karan, S. K., Osslund, F., Azzi, E. S., Karltun, E., &amp;amp; Sundberg, C. (2023). A spatial framework for prioritizing biochar application to arable land: A case study for Sweden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenyan biochar cookstoves</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/kenya-cookstove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/kenya-cookstove/</guid>
      <description>Resources Selected references Gitau, K. J.; Sundberg, C.; Mendum, R.; Mutune, J.; Njenga, M. Use of Biochar-Producing Gasifier Cookstove Improves Energy Use Efficiency and Indoor Air Quality in Rural Households. Energies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biochar water filters</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/6-water-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/6-water-filter/</guid>
      <description>Research is still ongoing Results will be revealed when the project has been completed. Contact: lisa.zakrisson@slu.se</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioenergy with or without CDR?</title>
      <link>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/8-bioenergy-cdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biochar.systems/case-studies/8-bioenergy-cdr/</guid>
      <description>Want to read more? Abstract Purpose
Bioenergy with carbon dioxide removal (CDR) is increasingly proposed as an efficient way to mitigate climate change. This study examined the circumstances and methodological choices in which two CDR bioenergy systems were preferable to a reference bioenergy system from a climate change mitigation perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
